{"question": "What is the association of telomere length with risk of mortality from influenza and pneumonia?", "answer": "shorter TL was associated with higher influenza-pneumonia mortality", "pmid": "37962763", "doi": "10.1007/s40520-023-02607-4", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How do the associations between telomere length and influenza-pneumonia mortality differ by sex?", "answer": "Men exhibited stronger associations with influenza-pneumonia mortality than women across all models. For example, in Model 1, the hazard ratio (HR) for men was 0.014 compared to 0.054 for women.", "pmid": "37962763", "doi": "10.1007/s40520-023-02607-4", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "What is the relationship between greenspace exposure and telomere length?", "answer": "Greater greenspace exposure in one's neighborhood was associated with longer telomere lengths ", "pmid": "37777139", "doi": "10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.167452", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "Did the relationship between greenspace and telomere length remain significant after adjusting for contextual factors?", "answer": "No, the relationship became non-significant when contextual factors, such as air pollution and deprivation, were included in the analysis.", "pmid": "37777139", "doi": "10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.167452", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How is telomere length (TL) related to bone mineral density (BMD) and bone mineral content (BMC)", "answer": " TL positively correlated with BMD and BMC in most body parts, but showed a negative correlation in the upper limbs and skull.", "pmid": "37744360", "doi": "10.3389/fimmu.2023.1181544", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "What is the relationship between telomere length and fat/muscle content?", "answer": "Fat content was negatively associated with TL, while muscle content was positively linked to TL.", "pmid": "37744360", "doi": "10.3389/fimmu.2023.1181544", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How did telomere length (TL) mediate the relationship between pollutant exposure and metabolic syndrome (MetS)?", "answer": "Principal component analysis showed that TL explained 26.1% of the effect of PC2 and 17.1% of PC4 on MetS risk in males, and 17.7% of the effect of PC2 on MetS in females.", "pmid": "37322399", "doi": "10.1017/S1368980023002008", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What model can be used to assess the relationship between exposure to a mixture of  environmental chemicals and metabolic syndrome (MetS) and further examined  whether telomere length (TL) moderated these relationships?", "answer": "The correlations between  multi-pollutant exposure, TL, and MetS in the males and females were separately  assessed using principal component analysis (PCA), logistic and extended linear  regression models, Bayesian kernel machine regression (BKMR), and mediation  analysis.", "pmid": "37322399", "doi": "10.1017/S1368980023002008", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What is the association between mixed exposure to polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) and telomere length in the adult general population?", "answer": "The  mixed exposure to polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) is negatively associated with telomere length in the adult general population.", "pmid": "37160859", "doi": "10.1007/s11356-023-27428-w", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How to analyze these associations of  telomere length in multiple PAH-exposed environments?", "answer": "Bayesian nuclear  machine regression (BKMR) was conducted to analyze these associations of  telomere length in multiple PAH-exposed environments. Linear regression is  mainly used for correlation analysis of PAHs with selected covariate  adjustments. Restricted cubic spline (RCS) is used to estimate the correlation  between selected PAHs and telomere length", "pmid": "37160859", "doi": "10.1007/s11356-023-27428-w", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What is the association of weight range with telomere length?", "answer": "In univariate linear regression, BMImax, BMI range, and weight range  all revealed significant negative associations with telomere length. However,  annual rate of BMI/weight range showed a significant positive associations with  telomere length.", "pmid": "37113487", "doi": "10.3389/fendo.2023.1106283", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "What is the association between leukocyte telomere length and cardiovascular mortality in type 2  diabetes patients?", "answer": "Longer LTL was  associated with reduced all-cause mortality, whereas this association  disappeared after adjusting for other variables. ", "pmid": "36890680", "doi": "10.1111/1753-0407.13376", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "What's the association between dietary vitamin C and telomere length?", "answer": "This cross-sectional study showed that vitamin C was positively  correlated with telomere length, with greater dietary vitamin C intake  associated with longer telomeres (\u03b2 = 0.03, 95% CI: 0.01-0.05, P = 0.003).", "pmid": "36776610", "doi": "10.3389/fnut.2023.1025936", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "What is the joint effect of leukocyte telomere length(LTL) and type 2 diabetes (T2D) on the risk of all-cause death?", "answer": "All-cause mortality has no significant difference between individuals with LTL in the highest tertile than individuals in the lowest tertile; but the individuals with T2D had a higher probability of death than individuals without. The joint effect of TLT and T2D was larger than the sum of the independent effects on the risk of all-cause death. Participants with high TLT and diabetes showed the highest possibility of death compared with other groups.", "pmid": "36440190", "doi": "10.3389/fendo.2022.1035017", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How to evaluate the effects of LTL and T2D status on death?", "answer": "Kaplan-Meier curves along with log-rank test", "pmid": "36440190", "doi": "10.3389/fendo.2022.1035017", "category": "method"}
{"question": "How to examine the links between TL and all-cause death possibility using adjusted hazard ratios (HRs)", "answer": "Cox proportional hazards models with adjustment for various confounders ", "pmid": "36440190", "doi": "10.3389/fendo.2022.1035017", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What are the association between urinary metals and leukocyte telomere length?", "answer": "The MLR results showed that urinary cadmium (Cd) was negatively correlated with LTL in the USA population [third quantile: -9.36, 95% confidential interval (CI) = (-19.7, -2.32)], and in the elderly urinary molybdenum (Mo) was positively associated with LTL [third quantile: 24.37, 95%CI = (5.42, 63.55)].", "pmid": "36172207", "doi": "10.3389/fpubh.2022.963138", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How did the research find the association between urinary metals and leukocyte telomere length involving an artificial neural network prediction?", "answer": "The analysis in this research had three steps including baseline difference comparison, multiple linear regression (MLR) for hazardous urine metals, and artificial neural network (ANN, based on Tensorflow framework) to make LTL prediction.", "pmid": "36172207", "doi": "10.3389/fpubh.2022.963138", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "What are the future direction if people want to study the association between urinary metals and leukocyte telomere length?", "answer": "In adults especially the elderly, the relationships between urinary Cd and Mo might be worthy of further research. ", "pmid": "36172207", "doi": "10.3389/fpubh.2022.963138", "category": "discussion"}
{"question": "What are the effects of active tobacco use and environmental tobacco smoke-measured through serum cotinine and mean telomere length?", "answer": "Serum cotinine was found to have an increasing effect on telomere length from age 37 to approximately age 74 among Mexican Americans. Among other/multi-race individuals serum cotinine was found to have a decreasing effect at approximately age 42, and among Blacks, it had an overall decreasing effect from age 61 to 78.", "pmid": "36078786", "doi": "10.3390/ijerph191711069", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How did researchers measured the differences between racial and ethnic groups in regards to the association of tobacco use and smoke exposure on mean telomere length?", "answer": "They used the time-varying effect modeling (TVEM), a nonparametric model requiring no constraints on shapes of intercept and slope functions.", "pmid": "36078786", "doi": "10.3390/ijerph191711069", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What is the major take-away from the authors about the time-varying effects of tabacco use in telomere length among multi-race individuals?", "answer": "Additional support and resources are needed to intervene regarding disparate health effects from tobacco use and environmental smoke exposure for already vulnerable groups at particular ages", "pmid": "36078786", "doi": "10.3390/ijerph191711069", "category": "discussion"}
{"question": "What is the association between leukocyte telomere length and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease?", "answer": "Short telomere length was associated with COPD, while C-reactive protein concentration, white blood cells count and blood neutrophil count, as inflammatory biomarkers, showed a significant indirect effect on the relationship between telomere length and COPD.", "pmid": "35987624", "doi": "10.1186/s12890-022-02114-8", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "What is the method used in measuring the association between leukocyte telomere length and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease?", "answer": "Multivariable-adjusted logistic regression and cubic regression spline analyses are used to calculate if short telomere length was associated with COPD.", "pmid": "35987624", "doi": "10.1186/s12890-022-02114-8", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What is the clinical implication for knowing the association between leukocyte telomere length and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease is partially mediated by inflammation?", "answer": "Telomere length measurement may facilitate clinical translational research and targeted therapy of COPD.", "pmid": "35987624", "doi": "10.1186/s12890-022-02114-8", "category": "discussion"}
{"question": "What is the association between visceral adiposity index and leukocyte telomere length in adults?", "answer": "Among all participants, visceral adiposity index was associated with the shorter LTL (\u03b2: -\u200914.81, 95% CI -\u200922.28 to -\u20097.34, p\u2009<\u20090.001).", "pmid": "35933575", "doi": "10.1007/s40520-022-02168-y", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "What is the association between triglyceride-glucose (TyG) index and telomere length?", "answer": "Five subgroups (TyG index 7.81-8.04, 8.04-8.21, 8.21-8.37, 8.37-8.52, and 8.52-8.68) did not show significant effect on LTL; while there was a significantly shorter LTL for participants with the TyG index > 8.68, supporting a threshold effect of TyG index on LTL.", "pmid": "35721750", "doi": "10.3389/fendo.2022.844073", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How are the homeostatic model assessment of insulin resistance (HOMA-IR) and triglyceride-glucose (TyG) index calculated?", "answer": "TyG index was calculated as ln [fasting triglycerides (mg/dL) \u00d7 fasting glucose (mg/dL)/2]. HOMA-Index was calculated as fasting plasma glucose (mmol/L) \u00d7 fasting serum insulin (mU/mL)/22.5.", "pmid": "35721750", "doi": "10.3389/fendo.2022.844073", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How did the researchers study the correlation between triglyceride-glucose (TyG) index, homeostatic model assessment of insulin resistance (HOMA-IR) and telomere length? ", "answer": "Multivariate linear regression analysis was assessed to evaluate the association of TyG index HOMA-IR with LTL. We further conducted a generalized additive model (GAM) and a fitted smoothing curve with penalized spline method.", "pmid": "35721750", "doi": "10.3389/fendo.2022.844073", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What is the association between dietary copper intake and telomere length in hypertension?", "answer": "One unit increasing log-transformed dietary copper intake in hypertension was significantly associated with longer telomere length base pair (bp) (\u03b2 = 112.20, 95% confidence interval [CI]: 5.48, 218.92), after controlling for covariates, including age, sex, ethnicity, body mass index (BMI), physical activity, and taking medication for hypertension", "pmid": "35587764", "doi": "10.1007/s12603-022-1787-7", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "What is the association between riboflavin intake and telomere length?", "answer": "There is a weak positive correlation between riboflavin intake and telomere length when unadjusted (\u03b2 = 0.011; P = 0.037) and adjusted for age, sex, and ethnicity (\u03b2 = 0.013; P = 0.033)", "pmid": "35433791", "doi": "10.3389/fnut.2022.744397", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "What method did the researcher use to study the association between Riboflavin intake and telomere length?", "answer": "Generalized linear regression is used to evaluate the \r\nassociation between dietary RF intake and telomere length along with other subgroup analyses. ", "pmid": "35433791", "doi": "10.3389/fnut.2022.744397", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What is the association of age at benign hysterectomy with leukocyte telomere length?", "answer": "Earlier age at benign hysterectomy was associated with shorter \r\ntelomere length in a nationally representative population of women after adjusting for other confounders, including age, race/ethnicity, education, marital status, income poverty ratio, body mass index (BMI), physical activity.", "pmid": "35337612", "doi": "10.1016/j.maturitas.2022.01.002", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How to calculate the association of age at benign hysterectomy with leukocyte telomere length?", "answer": "Multivariate regression analyses were used to estimate the association of age at benign hysterectomy with telomere length while adjusted for confounding factors, including age, race/ethnicity, education, marital status, income poverty ratio, body mass index(BMI), physical activity, smoking behavior, alcohol consumption, history of \r\nchronic disease and history of oophorectomy.", "pmid": "35337612", "doi": "10.1016/j.maturitas.2022.01.002", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What is the association between the oxidative balance score and telomere length according to the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 1999-2002?", "answer": "The association between the oxidative balance score and log-transformed LTL was positive in females but not males. And there is a gender difference in the \r\ncorrelations of the dietary OBS and the lifestyle OBS with log-transformed LTL.", "pmid": "35186180", "doi": "10.1155/2022/1345071", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "What method is used to study the association between the oxidative balance score and telomere length?", "answer": "The oxidative balance score is calculated using twenty dietary and lifestyle factors, and the association between oxidative balance score and log-transformed telomere length is assessed using multivariable linear regression.", "pmid": "35186180", "doi": "10.1155/2022/1345071", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What are the effects of aromatic air pollutants, such as Benzene, Toluene, Ethylbenzene, and Xylenes (BTEXs), in telomere length?", "answer": "Among the nonsmokers, the BTEXs mixture \r\nwas significantly inversely associated with TL at a low range of the BTEXs (20th-65th percentile) but was not associated with TL at a higher range (>65th percentile). ", "pmid": "35101395", "doi": "10.1016/j.envres.2022.112810", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How to measure the effect of the BTEXs mixture on TL adjusting for potential confounders?", "answer": "Bayesian Kernel Machine Regression (BKMR) is used in this research for its ability in flexible, non-linear relationships between multiple predictor variables and the response variable without needing to specify interaction terms explicitly.", "pmid": "35101395", "doi": "10.1016/j.envres.2022.112810", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What is the correlation between sarcopenic obesity and telomere shortening?", "answer": "Sarcopenic obesity (SO), defined as the presence of high \r\nadiposity-low muscle mass (four-phenotype model), had significantly shorter telomeres (p\u2009=\u20090.05) than the reference group.", "pmid": "34737398", "doi": "10.1038/s41366-021-00995-z", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How do we measure sarcopenic obesity (SO) in each individual?", "answer": "Two models \r\nwere used to assess SO: a BC model including four phenotypes derived from the \r\ncombination of high or low adiposity and muscle mass; and, a truncal fat mass to appendicular skeletal mass ratio (TrFM/ASM).", "pmid": "34737398", "doi": "10.1038/s41366-021-00995-z", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What is the model used to determine the associations between telomere length and sarcopenic obesity?", "answer": "A General Linear Model was applied to determine associations between telomere length and sarcopenic obesity.", "pmid": "34737398", "doi": "10.1038/s41366-021-00995-z", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What is the association of serum total bilirubin concentration with telomere length?", "answer": "Compared with the lowest concentration of total bilirubin (Q1), the highest quartile of total bilirubin concentration was associated with longer telomere length in males and females.", "pmid": "34603596", "doi": "10.1155/2021/4688900", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "What is the association of telomere length with liver disease and mortality?", "answer": "Shortened leukocyte telomere length is independently associated with advanced liver disease at older ages, and with a higher risk of all-cause mortality in those with liver disease.", "pmid": "34558851", "doi": "10.1002/hep4.1803", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How do researchers study the association of telomere lengths with liver disease and mortality?", "answer": "Cox regression model is used to evaluate associations between telomere length and all-cause mortality risk using adjusted hazard ratios, while multivariable-adjusted linear regression model is used to estimate effect sizes of liver disease on telomere length.", "pmid": "34558851", "doi": "10.1002/hep4.1803", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What is the association between endometriosis and telomere length? ", "answer": "Women with endometriosis had a shorter telomere length than women without endometriosis (-3.4, 95% CI: -7.3 to -0.3 in age-adjusted models and -2.9, 95% CI: -8.8 to 3.5 in fully adjusted models)", "pmid": "34449264", "doi": "10.1089/jwh.2021.0044", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "What is the association between weight changes and telomere length?", "answer": "People with stable obesity had shorter leukocyte telomere length than those with stable normal weight, while weight gain from non-obesity to obesity shortened the leukocyte telomere length.", "pmid": "34393992", "doi": "10.3389/fendo.2021.650988", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How do we measure the association between weight change and leukocyte telomere length?", "answer": "3,886 subjects aged 36-75 years from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES) 1999-2002 cycle were used to conduct the survey-weighted multivariable linear regression with adjustments for potential confounders.", "pmid": "34393992", "doi": "10.3389/fendo.2021.650988", "category": "method"}
{"question": "What is the association between fruit and vegetable intake and telomere length?", "answer": "Telomere length was linearly related to F&V intake when combined (F = 22.7, p < 0.0001) and also when separated as fruit (F = 7.2, p < 0.0121) or vegetables (F = 15.4, p < 0.0005), after adjusting for covariates. ", "pmid": "33922436", "doi": "10.3390/nu13051415", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "Is there a direct correlation between military service and telomere shortening?", "answer": "Yes, but only in men. The mean \r\ntelomere length for men was 47.2 (95% CI: -92.9, -1.5; p < 0.05) base pairs shorter for men with military service after adjustment for demographic, socioeconomic, and behavioral variables, but did not differ significantly in women with and without prior military service.", "pmid": "33670145", "doi": "10.3390/ijerph18041743", "category": "knowledge"}
{"question": "How do we properly adjust the covariates to measure the correlation between military service and telomere length?", "answer": "Mean telomere length in base pairs was analyzed with multivariable-adjusted linear regression with complex sample design, stratified by sex and adjusted for demographic, \r\nsocioeconomic, and behavioral variables.", "pmid": "33670145", "doi": "10.3390/ijerph18041743", "category": "method"}
{"question": "Test Question", "answer": "Test Answer", "pmid": "123456", "doi": "10.1234/example", "category": "knowledge"}
